#你看 這條小豬 現在長的好大啦
Look! The piglet has now grown up a lot.
#把它放到外面來
Since I've released it from the fence,
#吃得 像豬一樣那麼胖
it has been eating so much that it's now as fat as a pig.
#過來
Come here!
#別搖尾巴
Don't wiggle your tail!
#搖尾巴沒用的哦
There's no use wiggling your tail.
#要不然那個網來你網起來
Otherwise I'll catch you by the net.
#不聽話 現在
Naughty!
#現在長肥了一點
It's now getting a bit fatter.
#在外面
It can,
#要啥 要啥都可以吃
eat what, whatever it likes as it is outside the fence.
#被關起來的就沒辦法 出不來
Those who are fenced can't get out. They have no choices.
#不聽話 不次首先就烤它
Naughty! It'll be the first one to be grilled.
#這個攀蒲 (註︰以下三句村霸本身有語病，所以打算直譯，就是辭不達意也算了)
The "panpu" (pumpkins),
#讓它們
let them,
#來喂豬
feed the pigs.
#來 開飯咯 開飯咯
Come! It's meal time, meal time!
#這攀蒲 有點壞的 (註︰這裡不太明白村霸想說「這個南瓜壞了一點」還是「有一些南瓜是壞的」，我當作時前者)
The "pampu", is a bit rotten.
#搞點這個菜葉子 (註︰其實我不太清楚普通話的「青菜」和「菜葉子」的分別)
Give them some veggie.
#你看 不豬很喜歡吃這些攀蒲
Look! The piglets really love the "panpu".
#多餘的菜葉留給它們
The left over veggies are reserved for them.
#夠它們吃飽了
There's enough to get them stuffed.
#你看 外出幾天這些小豬
Look! The piglets are getting skinny during the days,
#都瘦了
when I'm not at home,
#特別是那兩條公的 小公豬
especially those two males ones, male piglets.
#更瘦了
They're even more skinny.
#多吃點啊 長肥點肉啊
Eat more and be more meaty!
#小豬
Piglet!
#這個
This,
#公 公豬
male, male pig,
#這條公的好小啊
this male pig is very small.
#摸都摸不到它的
I can't even touch it.
#你看 現在好像只有三十斤
Look! It now seems to be just 15 kg.
#又不怎麼大了
It doesn't really grow that much.
#外面那條還更胖
Even the one outside is fatter.
#你看 這公的
Look! This male pig,
#好壞的哦
is very nasty.
#摸一下臉
Let me touch your face.
#看你那縐紋
Look at your wrinkles!
#給你吃 我又不要
It's for you! I don't need it.
#過來
Come here!
I say come here!
#過來
Come here!
#那麼的
That male pig...
#上次被我打
It was beaten up by me last time.
#它現在看到我都怕了
It's now very scared of me.
#以前我還抱過你嘞 你還不知道嘞
I have hugged you before. I bet you can't remember.
#抱了你
I held you to,
(註︰原文沒有字幕，但我好像聽到「秤又枰又秤」之類的，覺得很有趣，所以都可以放字幕)
weigh and weigh and weigh.
#摸都不讓我摸一下
I can't even have a single touch.
#要不要抓來
Do you want,
#抓了你來秤一下
to be weighed?
#這條太大了 秤不了重
This is now too big to be weighed.
#好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here,
#這 讓它們吃 吃飽一點 (註︰不太清楚是分兩句還是口吃)
Just let them eat more, get them stuffed.